kentessa.com 2016-11-25

# Kentessa.com - Privacy Policy

## Kentessa.com Privacy Statement 

## A. What is Personal Information? 

Personal information is information that identifies an individual or is directly associated with a specific person or entity such as a name, address, telephone number, email address, credit card number, or information about activities which can be directly linked to that person, such as his or her purchases.

Our definition of personal information does not include "aggregate" information. Aggregate information is data we collect about a group or category of products, services or website visitors, from which individual identities have been removed. In other words, information about how you use a service may be collected and combined with information about how others use the same service, but no personal information will be included in the resulting data. Likewise, information about the products you purchase may be collected and combined with information about the products purchased by others. Aggregate data helps us understand trends and online visitors needs so that we can better consider new products and services, and tailor existing products and services to our clients’ desires.

## B. Collection of Personal Information

We collect the personal information that you provide us, such as when you:

sign up for or register on Kentessa.com;

register to use Kentessa.com or sign up for news or notifications of specials or other promotions on Kentessa.com;

place an order or purchase products or services at our online store or over the phone;

contact us for any reason, such as by replying to inquires by mail, fax or through our website, by telephone through customer service, or in person at one of our locations; or

We may automatically collect some information when you visit our website, such as your computer's network address and operating system, the site from which you linked to us, your site activity and the time and date of your visit and purchases. This information may be collected through the use of "cookies" (see Online Specifics below). We also receive information from third parties who provide services or special promotions or products and we may combine this information with the other personal information we maintain about you. In either case, this policy statement governs this information.

## C. Use of Personal Information by Kentessa.com

The personal information we collect is generally used to process your requests or transactions, provide you with high-quality service, tell you about opportunities we think will be of interest, and understand your needs so that we can serve you better. For example, we may use your telephone number, your email or your postal address to: (1) alert you about product recalls or safety issues; or (2) special opportunities and programs. We also may use personal information we collect to provide you with promotional information, which is information we believe will add value to your shopping, such as coupons or promotions. If you prefer not to receive Promotional Information from us, we make it easy for you to let us know. You may contact us at any time to decline Promotional Information (see Choice below).

## D. Sharing of Personal Information

We do not sell, rent, share or disclose personal information to third parties without your prior consent, except in the limited circumstances described below:

### 1\. Order Fulfillment

We may provide to a third party information that is necessary to fulfill an order you have placed with us. For example, if you request shipment for a purchase, we may provide your address to the shipping carrier, and if you pay by a credit or debit card, your card number and sales transaction information are passed on to the card processor and/or issuer (including their service providers such as fraud verification services). However, we give suppliers, and others involved in the commerce distribution chain only the information needed to provide you the products or services you order, such as shipping and/or billing address, email address, telephone number and product orders. Moreover, we require them to keep the information confidential and not to use it for other purposes. We are not responsible for any additional information you provide directly to these parties, and we encourage you to become familiar with their practices before disclosing information directly to them.

### 2\. Our Contractors

We may contract with others to perform tasks or services on our behalf. For example, we might retain a company to process credit card payments, to email information about special offers, or to analyze data. If any of our contractors need access to your personal information, we require that they promise to use the information only to perform the tasks we have engaged them to perform. We also require that they maintain the confidentiality of the information and/or return the information to us when they no longer need it.

## E. Other Uses and Disclosures

In addition, we may use or disclose personal information in the good faith belief that we are lawfully authorized to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to protect you, to comply with legal process or authorities, to respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of Kentessa.com, our clients, our employees or the public.

## F. Protection of Personal and Credit Card Information

We have adopted security measures in an effort to protect personal information from loss, misuse or alteration while it is under our control. We use technical, contractual, administrative and physical measures in an effort to protect against unauthorized access. Personal information we collect is stored electronically.

We collect, process and maintain payment information, including credit card information, in compliance with the data security rules adopted by credit card companies such as Visa, MasterCard and American Express. This means that we do not retain debit card PINs or credit card security codes, and that any time we maintain a credit card number, such as when you create an online account, we use access controls and strong encryption to protect it. Further, when you enter personal information online, that information is encrypted using a security protocol called SSL (Secure Sockets Layer), which encrypts all information prior to transmitting it over the Internet. We also use SSL to allow you to securely view your online account and registration information.

Online account information is accessible only by using a password. To protect the confidentiality of personal information in your online account, you must keep your password confidential. You are responsible for all uses of [www.kentessa.com](http://www.kentessa.com/) by anyone using your password. If others have access to your computer or email, they may be able to find your password and obtain information about you (such as your address or phone number), or change information in your user profile. You should not use an email account operated by an employer because many employers have the legal right to view your email or online accounts. Please advise us immediately at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php) if you believe your password has been misused.

## G. Choice

We give you the opportunity to opt-out of receiving certain information or to request that certain information not be shared with third parties, by giving you numerous methods to inform us of your decision. Your choice to opt-out will not apply to your spouse and any add-on members.

1\. If you do not want us to share information with third parties, you can: (a) call our customer service representatives at (04) 259 1261; (b) email us at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php);

2\. If you do not want to receive Promotional Information (see Use of Personal Information by Kentessa.com) or information about related services, you can: (a) call our customer service representatives at (04) 259 1261; (b) email us at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php);

3\. If you do not want to receive promotional emails, you can: (a) call our customer service representatives at (04) 259 1261; (b) email us at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php);

## H. Online Specifics

### 1\. What Are Cookies and Are You Required to Accept Them?

Cookies are small files that are stored on your computer. At Kentessa.com, we use cookies to help optimize your shopping experience. For example, we use cookies to customize our home page for you and to better display pages according to your browser type. Kentessa.com does not store in cookies any personal information about you.

While cookies are optional for browsing Kentessa.com, they are required for registering, logging on, shopping or adding items to your cart. If you wish to purchase items or set up an account on Kentessa.com, you will need to accept a Kentessa.com cookie.

### 2\. Use of the Kentessa.com Web Site by Children

We encourage parents to take an active interest in their children's use of the Internet. We do not intend to collect information from children who are under 18 years of age. If you are under 18, you should not provide information on the Kentessa.com Website and should ask your parent to do so for you.

### 3\. Online Links to Other Web Sites

Through selected portions of our website, you can link to other websites of third parties who have agreed to offer goods and services to our members. Any personal information you provide on the linked pages is provided directly to that third party and is subject to that third party's privacy policy. Except as described above, we are not responsible for the content or privacy and security practices and policies of websites to which we link. Links from our site to third parties or to other sites are provided for your convenience. We encourage you to learn about their privacy and security practices and policies before providing them with personal information.

### 4\. Updating, Reviewing or Correcting Online Personal Information

You may update, review or correct your online account information at any time online by accessing your password-protected registration page via the "My Account" area of the Web site. You also may email us at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php) or call us at (04) 259 1261.

### 5\. Retention of Information we Collect Online

Information we automatically collect as a result of your online activity is generally not retained in a personally identifiable form, or if the information is personally identifiable, we retain it only long enough for us to perform studies and analyses related to our website. The exception would be information we need in order to investigate fraud or problems associated with particular transactions or events.

## I. Questions or Concerns

If you have any questions or concerns about this privacy statement or would like to contact us for any reason, you can do the following:

1\. Call our Customer Service representatives at (04) 259 1261;  
2\. Email us at [Email US](http://www.kentessa.com/email_us.php); or

## J. Changes to this Statement

We reserve the right to change this privacy statement at any time, but will alert you that changes have been made by indicating at the top of the privacy statement the date it was last updated. We encourage you to review our privacy statement to make sure you understand how information you provide will be used. If there is ever a material change to how we use information you provide and the new uses are unrelated to uses we disclose in this statement, we will communicate the changes in advance.
